Eamon Grennan papers, 1964-2010
Emory University
- Writings by Grennan, 1962-2010, Series 2; Boxes 3 - 53; BV 1 - 3
  - Poetry, 1962-2010, Subseries 2.1; Boxes 3 - 39
    - Collected poetry, 1972-2010, Subseries 2.1a; Boxes 3 - 20
      - "Sons" [Variant titles: "Medusa," "Face," and "Brief Exposures"] (Box 9, Folder 5)
      - "Spring Fever" [Variant title: "In this Spring"] (Box 9, Folder 6)
      - "Statue" (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - "Stone Flight" (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - "Swan in Winter" [Variant title: "Swan"] (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - "These Northern Fields at Dusk" [Variant title: "Northern Fields at Dusk"] (Box 9, Folder 10)
      - "Through Glass" (Box 9, Folder 11)
      - "Towards Dusk the Porcupine" (Box 9, Folder 12)
      - "Two for the Road" [Variant titles: "Smoke" and "Shapes"] (Box 9, Folder 13)
      - "Visiting Mount Jerome" [Variant titles: "Visit to Mount Jerome" and "Two Visits to Mount Jerome"] (Box 9, Folder 14)
      - "Wet Morning, Clareville Road" (Box 9, Folder 15)
      - "What Doesn't Happen" (Box 9, Folder 16)
      - "Whistling in the Dark" [Variant titles: "Preliminary Sketches of My Dead Mother" and "Preliminary Sketches"] (Box 9, Folder 17)
      - "Women Going" (Box 9, Folder 18)
      - Facing Silence [Variant title of So It Goes], typescript draft [Photocopy] (Box 9, Folder 19)
      - Natural Causes [Variant title of So It Goes], typescript draft (Box 9, Folder 20)
      - Natural Causes [Variant title of So It Goes], typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 9, Folder 21)
      - So It Goes, author questionnaire (Box 9, Folder 22)
      - So It Goes, catalog copy (Box 9, Folder 23)
      - So It Goes, editorial correspondence (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - So It Goes, front matter drafts (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - So It Goes, galley proof [Photocopy with annotations], July 12, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - So It Goes, towards So It Goes (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - So It Goes, towards So It Goes (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - So It Goes, typescript draft (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - So It Goes, typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - So It Goes, typescript draft, June 1-4, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - So It Goes, typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations], June 4, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - Still Life with Waterfall [Variant title of So It Goes], typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 10, Folder 9)
      - Still Life with Waterfall [Variant title of So It Goes], typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence], March 1, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
      - Relations: New and Selected Poems (1998)
      - "Couple on Park Bench" (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - "Streak of Light" (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - "Weather" (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - Relations, cover art designs [Includes correspondence] (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - Relations, editorial correspondence, circa 1997-1998 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - Relations, front matter drafts [Includes correspondence] (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - Relations, galley proof, May 4, 1998 [1 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 1)
      - Relations, galley proof, May 4, 1998 [2 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 2)
      - Relations, galley proof sample pages, April 8, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      - Relations, galley proof sample pages, April 14, 1998 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      - Relations, poems considered for Relations (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Relations, statement by Grennan about Relations (Box 11, Folder 6)
      - Relations, towards Relations (Box 11, Folder 7)
      - Relations, towards Relations (Box 11, Folder 8)
      - Relations, towards Relations [1 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 9)
      - Relations, towards Relations [2 of 2] (Box 11, Folder 10)
      - Relations, typescript draft, first [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Relations, typescript draft, second (Box 12, Folder 1)
      - Selected and New Poems (2000)
      - Editorial correspondence (Box 12, Folder 2)
      - Table of contents drafts (Box 12, Folder 3)
      - Still Life with Waterfall (2001)
      - "After Rain" (Box 12, Folder 4)
      - "Agnostic Smoke" (Box 12, Folder 5)
      - "Anti-Psalm" (Box 12, Folder 6)
      - "Ash" (Box 12, Folder 7)
      - "Bonnard's Reflection" (Box 12, Folder 8)
      - "Butterfly, Breath, Small Birds" (Box 12, Folder 9)
      - "Country Road" (Box 12, Folder 10)
      - "Current Events" (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - "Design" (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - "Detail" (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - "Enough" (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - "Eye Trouble" (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - "Hare" (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - "In the Dunes" (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - "Killing the Bees" (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - "Landscape with Teeth" [Variant title: "Sketchpad"] (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - "Rainbow Skirt" (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - "Shepherd to the Wind" (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - "Shock Waves" (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - "Vespers" (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - "Why?" (Box 12, Folder 24)
      - "Wind Chimes" (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - "Windowgrave" (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Body of Knowledge [Variant title of Still Life with Waterfall], typescript draft, first (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, author questionnaire (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, book jacket (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, cover art designs (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, editorial correspondence, circa 2000-2002 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, front matter drafts (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, poems considered for but not included in Still Life with Waterfall (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, poems considered for but not included in Still Life with Waterfall (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, towards Still Life with Waterfall (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, towards Still Life with Waterfall (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 13, Folder 2)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft [Photocopy with annotations] (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft [Photocopy] (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft, penultimate (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Still Life with Waterfall, typescript draft, final [Photocopy], May 22, 2001 (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Renvyle, Winter (2003)
      - "In This World" (Box 14, Folder 1)
      - "Morning Offering, Renvyle" (Box 14, Folder 2)
      - Renvyle, Winter, front matter drafts (Box 14, Folder 3)
      - Renvyle, Winter, galley proof, September 12, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 4)
      - Renvyle, Winter, model with original artwork [Includes editorial correspondence], circa 1999-2002 (Box 14, Folder 5)
      - Renvyle, Winter, towards Renvyle, Winter, winter 1997 (Box 14, Folder 6)
      - Renvyle, Winter, typescript draft (Box 14, Folder 7)
      - Renvyle, Winter, typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence], January 12, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 8)
      - Renvyle: Winter Glimmers [Variant title of Renvyle, Winter], typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence] (Box 14, Folder 9)
      - The Quick of It (2004)
      - Days of 2000 [Variant title of The Quick of It], poems considered for but not included in Days of 2000 (Box 14, Folder 10)
      - Days of 2000 [Variant title of The Quick of It], towards Days of 2000 [1 of 2] (Box 14, Folder 11)
      - Days of 2000 [Variant title of The Quick of It], towards Days of 2000 [2 of 2] (Box 14, Folder 12)
      - Days of 2000 [Variant title of The Quick of It], towards Days of 2000 [1 of 2] (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Days of 2000 [Variant title of The Quick of It], towards Days of 2000 [2 of 2] (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - The Quick of It, cover art designs (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - The Quick of It, front matter drafts (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - The Quick of It, galley proof, June 10, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - The Quick of It, typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - The Quick of It, typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - The Quick of It, typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 7)
      - The Quick of It, typescript draft (Box 15, Folder 8)
      - The Quick of It, typescript draft, May 20, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 9)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, first (Box 15, Folder 10)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, second, July 2003 (Box 15, Folder 11)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, third (Box 16, Folder 1)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, fourth (Box 16, Folder 2)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, fifth (Box 16, Folder 3)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, sixth, October 2003 (Box 16, Folder 4)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, seventh [Photocopy with annotations, includes editorial correspondence] (Box 16, Folder 5)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, eighth, February 2004 (Box 16, Folder 6)
      - What Matter [Variant title of The Quick of It], typescript draft, ninth (Box 16, Folder 7)
      - Out of Breath (2007)
      - "Discovery" (Box 16, Folder 8)
      - "Edge" (Box 16, Folder 9)
      - "Hawklight" [Variant title: "Brace of Hawks"] (Box 16, Folder 10)
      - "Something" (Box 16, Folder 11)
      - Out of Breath, front matter drafts (Box 16, Folder 12)
      - Out of Breath, poems considered for but not included in Out of Breath (Box 16, Folder 13)
      - Out of Breath, typescript draft (Box 16, Folder 14)
      - Out of Breath, typescript draft (Box 16, Folder 15)
      - Out of Breath, typescript draft (Box 16, Folder 16)
      - Out of Breath, typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Out of Breath, typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 2)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft, first (Box 17, Folder 3)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft, second (Box 17, Folder 4)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft, third (Box 17, Folder 5)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft (Box 17, Folder 6)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft [Includes correspondence] (Box 17, Folder 7)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft, May 2006 (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Steady [Variant title of Out of Breath], typescript draft [Photocopy], June 2006 (Box 17, Folder 9)
      - Matter of Fact (2008)
      - "Photo of Matisse" (Box 17, Folder 10)
      - Matter of Fact, editorial correspondence (Box 17, Folder 11)
      - Matter of Fact, front matter drafts (Box 17, Folder 12)
      - Matter of Fact, towards Matter of Fact [1 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Matter of Fact, towards Matter of Fact [2 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 2)
      - Matter of Fact, towards Matter of Fact [3 of 3] (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Matter of Fact, towards Matter of Fact, January-February 2005 [1 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Matter of Fact, towards Matter of Fact, January-February 2005 [2 of 2] (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 6)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 8)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 18, Folder 9)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 1)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 2)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 3)
      - Matter of Fact, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Out of Sight: New and Selected Poems (2010)
      - "In the Kitchen with Yeats" (Box 19, Folder 5)
      - Out of Sight, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 6)
      - Out of Sight, typescript draft, 2007-2008 (Box 19, Folder 7)
      - Out of Sight, typescript draft, April 15, 2009 (Box 19, Folder 8)
      - Other volumes
      - No date, Close Quarters [Variant title: Sketch Book], typescript draft [Photocopy] (Box 19, Folder 9)
      - No date, Three in the Morning, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 10)
      - No date, unidentified publication, typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence] (Box 19, Folder 11)
      - 1972 March 26, Rituals in an Empty Room, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 12)
      - 1973 March 26, Under All Weathers, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 13)
      - 1975 April, Starting Out, typescript draft (Box 19, Folder 14)
      - 1976 March 26, Spring Harvest, typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 1)
      - 1981, Cyphers, number 15, typescript draft [Includes editorial correspondence] (Box 20, Folder 2)
      - 1997 April 8, "Filíocht Nua: New Poetry," galley proof, New Hibernia Review (Box 20, Folder 3)
      - 1997 autumn, Metre 3, typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 4)
      - 1999 January 18, Poetry Ireland Review 60, proof (Box 20, Folder 5)
      - 2001 spring, Metre 9, galley proof (Box 20, Folder 6)
      - 2002-2003 winter, Metre 13, typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 7)
      - 2005, Daughter Sketches, typescript draft (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Uncollected poetry, circa 1960s-2010, Subseries 2.1b; Boxes 21 - 31
      The subseries contains uncollected poems by Grennan. Some of these poems were published in journals and magazines. Most poems have multiple drafts with revisions, which are arranged in the same folder. The majority of the drafts are undated, so internal organization does not reflect draft order in most cases. Duplicate folder titles in the container list reflect Grennan's reuse of the same titles for different poems.
      Arranged in alphabetical order.
      - "[?] Painting" (Box 21, Folder 1)
      - "About the House" [Variant title: "Things about the House" (Box 21, Folder 2)
      - "Advice to Writing Student" (Box 21, Folder 3)
      - "After a Death, a Walk in the Country" [Variant title: "Steps"] (Box 21, Folder 4)
      - "After a Dry Spell, Rain" (Box 21, Folder 5)
      - "After Fever" [Variant titles: "Uninvited," "Passage," and "Passing"] (Box 21, Folder 6)
      - "After Images" (Box 21, Folder 7)
      - "After Rain" (Box 21, Folder 8)
      - "After Schindler's List" (Box 21, Folder 9)
      - "After Winter" (Box 21, Folder 10)
      - "Afterlight" (Box 21, Folder 11)
      - "Aftermath: The Soul as Fragrance" (Box 21, Folder 12)
      - "Again" (Box 21, Folder 13)
      - "The All Clear" (Box 21, Folder 14)
      - "All Saints' Day" (Box 21, Folder 15)
      - "Alli" [Variant title: "Alli Dying"] (Box 21, Folder 16)
      - "Allusion Illusion" (Box 21, Folder 17)
      - "Aloft" (Box 21, Folder 18)
      - "Ambition" (Box 21, Folder 19)
      - "Amen to That" [Variant title: "What the Day Might Hold"] (Box 21, Folder 20)
      - "Amphibian" (Box 21, Folder 21)
      - "Amulet" (Box 21, Folder 22)
      - "Andreas" (Box 21, Folder 23)
      - "Anniversary" [Variant title: "Nine"] (Box 21, Folder 24)
      - "Another Walk: Night Falling" (Box 21, Folder 25)
      - "Approximating" (Box 21, Folder 26)
      - "April Again" (Box 21, Folder 27)
      - "April Fools' Day" (Box 21, Folder 28)
      - "April Twenty-third" (Box 21, Folder 29)
      - "April 30, 1993" (Box 21, Folder 30)
      - "Arrival" (Box 21, Folder 31)
      - "Arrival MacDowell" [Variant title: "Arrival"] (Box 21, Folder 32)
      - "Ars Poetica Again" (Box 21, Folder 33)
      - "Art Gallery Sketch" (Box 21, Folder 34)
      - "Artist at Work" (Box 21, Folder 35)
      - "Ash Wednesday Unicorn" (Box 21, Folder 36)
      - "Aspects of Travel" (Box 21, Folder 37)
      - "At a Loss" (Box 21, Folder 38)
      - "At an Angle" (Box 21, Folder 39)
      - "At First" (Box 21, Folder 40)
      - "At Home" [Variant title: "Home Thoughts"] (Box 21, Folder 41)
      - "At the P.T.A. Fair in Poughkeepsie" (Box 21, Folder 42)
      - "Attention" (Box 21, Folder 43)
      - "Attention Span" (Box 21, Folder 44)
      - "Aubade for Rachel" (Box 21, Folder 45)
      - "Autumn" [Variant title: "Fire and Ice"] (Box 21, Folder 46)
      - "Babel" (Box 21, Folder 47)
      - "Back Porch" (Box 21, Folder 48)
      - "Back Road" [Variant title: "Bad Night Back Road"] (Box 21, Folder 49)
      - "Back to Basics" (Box 21, Folder 50)
      - "Bag Lady with Branch" (Box 21, Folder 51)
      - "Balancing Act" (Box 21, Folder 52)
      - "Bales of Hay in October Morning" (Box 21, Folder 53)
      - "Ballymoney 1978" (Box 21, Folder 54)
      - "Ballymoney Sketches, March 1978" (Box 21, Folder 55)
      - "Beasts Unseen" (Box 21, Folder 56)
      - "Begin Again Midsummer" (Box 21, Folder 57)
      - "Behind the Poem" (Box 21, Folder 58)
      - "Berryman 12 1/2" (Box 21, Folder 59)
      - "Bestiary" (Box 21, Folder 60)
      - "Beyond" (Box 21, Folder 61)
      - "Beyond the Big Words" (Box 21, Folder 62)
      - "The Big House" (Box 21, Folder 63)
      - "Big Wind Small Bird" (Box 21, Folder 64)
      - "Biological Senility" (Box 21, Folder 65)
      - "Bird and Beast, Renvyle" (Box 21, Folder 66)
      - "Bird Garden" [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Robin in Thornbush"] (Box 21, Folder 67)
      - "Bird the First Morning" (Box 21, Folder 68)
      - "Birds" (Box 21, Folder 69)
      - "Birds and Other Voyagers in Late October" (Box 21, Folder 70)
      - "Bird's Eye View" (Box 21, Folder 71)
      - "Bird-Watching" (Box 21, Folder 72)
      - "Birthday" (Box 21, Folder 73)
      - "Birthday" [Variant title: "May 4, My Father's Birthday"] (Box 21, Folder 74)
      - "Birthday Verse, March 26" (Box 21, Folder 75)
      - "Bite" [Variant title: "Sting"] (Box 21, Folder 76)
      - "Blackout" (Box 21, Folder 77)
      - "Blaze" (Box 21, Folder 78)
      - "Blood, Nest, Stars" (Box 21, Folder 79)
      - "Blossoming Elm" (Box 21, Folder 80)
      - "Boats" (Box 21, Folder 81)
      - "Body" (Box 21, Folder 82)
      - "Bodies" (Box 21, Folder 83)
      - "Bonfire Night" (Box 21, Folder 84)
      - "Book of Knowledge" (Box 21, Folder 85)
      - "Border Country" (Box 21, Folder 86)
      - "Border Patrol" [Variant titles: "Border Crossing," "Change, Its Conjugations," and "Conjugating Change"] (Box 21, Folder 87)
      - "Bosola in Solitary" (Box 22, Folder 1)
      - "Boys Walking" (Box 22, Folder 2)
      - "Brave New World" (Box 22, Folder 3)
      - "The Breaking Season" (Box 22, Folder 4)
      - "Breath" (Box 22, Folder 5)
      - "Breathing" (Box 22, Folder 6)
      - "Bright and Dark" (Box 22, Folder 7)
      - "Bright Interval in Vermont" [Variant title: "Bright Intervals"] (Box 22, Folder 8)
      - "Broken Statues" (Box 22, Folder 9)
      - "Brother and Sister" (Box 22, Folder 10)
      - "Brother Mole" (Box 22, Folder 11)
      - "The Budgies Beheaded in Derry" (Box 22, Folder 12)
      - "Building" (Box 22, Folder 13)
      - "Building" (Box 22, Folder 14)
      - "Building Site" (Box 22, Folder 15)
      - "A Bunch of Dates" (Box 22, Folder 16)
      - "Burial" (Box 22, Folder 17)
      - "Burial" [Variant titles: "Burials" and "Another Burial"] (Box 22, Folder 18)
      - "Burn" [Variant title: "Burning Question"] (Box 22, Folder 19)
      - "Bush and Ruined Building" [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Love's Morning"] (Box 22-, Folder 20-)
      - "But So" (Box 22, Folder 21)
      - "By Chance: Shadow Music" (Box 22, Folder 22)
      - "Calder's Dream" (Box 22, Folder 23)
      - "Calendar Art" (Box 22, Folder 24)
      - "The Call" (Box 22, Folder 25)
      - "The Camera Never Lies" (Box 22, Folder 26)
      - "Cardinal" (Box 22, Folder 27)
      - "Cardinal in November" (Box 22, Folder 28)
      - "Cartography" (Box 22, Folder 29)
      - "Catbird by Doglight" (Box 22, Folder 30)
      - "Catch" (Box 22, Folder 31)
      - "Cave" (Box 22, Folder 32)
      - "Cave and Awakening" (Box 22, Folder 33)
      - "Cell" (Box 22, Folder 34)
      - "Certain Age" (Box 22, Folder 35)
      - "Chain" (Box 22, Folder 36)
      - "A Change of Direction" (Box 22, Folder 37)
      - "A Change of Light in Provincetown" (Box 22, Folder 38)
      - "Child's Play" (Box 22, Folder 39)
      - "The Chilean Singer" (Box 22, Folder 40)
      - "Chrysalis" (Box 22, Folder 41)
      - "Church Bells in Poughkeepsie" (Box 22, Folder 42)
      - "Circle" (Box 22, Folder 43)
      - "City Wildflowers" [Also includes "Patient in Pat's"] (Box 22, Folder 44)
      - "Class Preparation" (Box 22, Folder 45)
      - "Clean-Up" (Box 22, Folder 46)
      - "Clearance" (Box 22, Folder 47)
      - "Cold Spring Florist" (Box 22, Folder 48)
      - "The Coming Day" (Box 22, Folder 49)
      - "Coming Forth" (Box 22, Folder 50)
      - "Coming Through" (Box 22, Folder 51)
      - "Coming Through" (Box 22, Folder 52)
      - "Comme Je Trouve" [Variant title: "Daughter"] (Box 22, Folder 53)
      - "Communion" (Box 22, Folder 54)
      - "Connection" (Box 22, Folder 55)
      - "Conor at Twelve" [Variant title: "Conor, Time, and Space"] (Box 22, Folder 56)
      - "Containing" (Box 22, Folder 57)
      - "Contemporary Torso, Not Apollo" (Box 22, Folder 58)
      - "Convalescent" (Box 22, Folder 59)
      - "Conversation" (Box 22, Folder 60)
      - "Corporal Ties" (Box 22, Folder 61)
      - "Correspondence" (Box 22, Folder 62)
      - "Could This Be It?" (Box 22, Folder 63)
      - "Country Matters" (Box 22, Folder 64)
      - "Couple" (Box 22, Folder 65)
      - "Couple" [ee "February Haiku"] (Box 22, Folder 66)
      - "Couple" [Variant title: "Two Red-Breasted Mergansers"] (Box 22, Folder 67)
      - "The Couple" [see "The Spring"] (Box 22, Folder 68)
      - "Couples" (Box 22, Folder 69)
      - "Couples at Bus Stop" (Box 22, Folder 70)
      - "Cows" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Painter and Subject"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Cows on a Windy Day" [See Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "February Haiku"] (Box -, Folder -)
      - "Cricket in the Cellar" (Box 22, Folder 71)
      - "Crossing the Border" (Box 22, Folder 72)
      - "Crossing Water" (Box 22, Folder 73)
      - "Cuckoo" (Box 22, Folder 74)
      - "Cuisle" (Box 22, Folder 75)
      - "Dance" (Box 22, Folder 76)
      - "Daphne's Dilemma" (Box 22, Folder 77)
      - "Daughter and Dying Fish" (Box 22, Folder 78)
      - "Daughter and Memory" (Box 22, Folder 79)
      - "Daughter's Silk" [Variant title: "Silk"] (Box 22, Folder 80)
      - "Dawn Chorus at Le Pitturacce" (Box 22, Folder 81)
      - "Dawn near Gurteen" (Box 22, Folder 82)
      - "The Day I Leave Renvyle" (Box 22, Folder 83)
      - "Day of Rain" (Box 22, Folder 84)
      - "Dead Flowers" (Box 22, Folder 85)
      - "A Decade for A.C." (Box 22, Folder 86)
      - "December Bedroom" (Box 22, Folder 87)
      - "Deceptions" (Box 23, Folder 1)
      - "Deep Water" (Box 23, Folder 2)
      - "Deeper In" (Box 23, Folder 3)
      - "Deer Vanishing" (Box 23, Folder 4)
      - "Departure MacDowell" (Box 23, Folder 5)
      - "Desert" (Box 23, Folder 6)
      - "Design" [See also Subseries 2.1b: Uncollected poetry, "Glimmers of a City"] (Box 23, Folder 7)
      - "Desire" (Box 23, Folder 8)
      - "Desire" (Box 23, Folder 9)
      - "Discovery, Vermont" (Box 23, Folder 10)
      - "Distraction" (Box 23, Folder 11)
      - "Distraction of a Local Pain" (Box 23, Folder 12)
      - "Diver Decked" [Variant title: "Diver on Deck"] (Box 23, Folder 13)